# **Software Engineer**

## **Christian Howe**

### **PROFILE**

I have been programming for 13 years, starting at the age of 12. I am interested in working with iOS mobile software, web development, and software engineering, especially in a functional style. My especially broad knowledge and high adaptability is due to much of my experience coming from personal experience in open source software. I am looking for a full-time position in front-end or full-stack software engineering.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

**SOFTWARE ENGINEER, THE NEW OFFICE, AUSTIN, TX** JAN 2016 - DEC 2016 I worked on an Elm frontend and Elixir backend for data integration technology at The New Office. This included doing a major pull request over many weeks to add support for connecting to a distributed MongoDB topology by conforming to their client specification.

SUPPORT ENGINEER, NODEJITSU; REMOTE MAR 2012 - APR 2013

I started at Nodejitsu in high school, where I worked on Github pull requests for Node.js backend server software while providing technical support to other engineers using the hosting platform. Nodejitsu was bought out by GoDaddy.

## FREELANCER, REMOTE 2005 - PRESENT

I have been freelancing on and off since I started programming. These projects include iOS mobile applications, React, Redux and GraphQL full-stack websites, mobile and desktop cryptocurrency clients in Qt, and many other smaller projects in Unity 3D and other technologies.

## **EDUCATION**

VIRGINIA TECH - COMPUTER SCIENCE, FALL 2018

#### SKILLS

iOS, XCode, Swift, MVC

HTML, CSS and SASS

Javascript/ES6 (babel, webpack)

· Functional Programming, Elm

Node.js and npm/yarn

Elixir, OTP, distributed systems

React, Redux, Next.js, Gatsby

Git/Github and open source

RxJS, RxSwift, MVVM

MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Firebase

· GraphQL/Apollo

· Linux, OS X and Windows